So there are two correct answers, the third one, and
所以这里有两个正确答案 第三个和
the fifth one. And this is why a hash table is such a great
第五个 这就是为什么哈希表比
advance over the linear index, is that we can double the number of keywords, and
线性索引更好的原因 我们可以加倍关键词数目
double the number of buckets, and the look up
加倍桶的数目 但是查询时间
time stays the same. With the linear index, if we
保持不变 而对于线性索引 如果我们
double the number of keywords for each look up, we
加倍关键词数目 那么对每次查询
need to go through the loop once for each keyword.
我们都需要遍历每一个关键词
If the keyword was near the end or one that wasn't
如果关键词在最后 或者根本不在
in the table, the time to look up the keyword would
表里面 则查询的时间会
double as we double the number of keywords. With a hash
随着我们加倍关键词的数目而加倍 使用
table if we also double the number of buckets when we double
哈希表的时候 如果我们同时加倍桶的数目 在我们
the number of keywords, well then the number of keywords in
加倍关键词数目时 那么每个桶里的关键词
each bucket stays the same. We're dividing the keywords evenly between
数目保持不变 我们正在将关键词均匀分配到桶中
buckets. So this is the number, the number of keywords per
因此 这就是那个数字 每个桶的关键词数量
bucket is the number of keywords divided by the number of buckets.
是关键词的数量除以桶的数量
If we double both, that number stays approximately the same. The
如果我们对它们都加倍 这个数字几乎保持不变
time to look up only depends on the number of keywords per
查询时间只取决于每个桶的关键词数量
bucket. The time to find the bucket is very fast, right? We
找到桶的时间非常快 对吧？
just need to run the hash function, find that element of the
我们只需要运行哈希函数 找到列表的元素
list. Both of those don't depend on the size of the
这两个查询需要多久时间
list, how long it takes to do that. And then we have
都和列表的尺寸没多大关系 然后我们要
to look through the bucket, the size of the bucket, we have
遍历找到的桶 根据桶的尺寸 我们必须
to look though each element in the bucket one at a time.
一次遍历该桶的每个元素
So if we keep the number of key words per bucket
因此 如果我们保持每个桶的关键词数量相同
the same, the look up time stays essentially the same. So that's
则查找时间保持基本相同 所以这是
the great property that hash tables have. If we double the
哈希表所拥有的很强大的一个特性 如果我们加倍了
number of buckets, as we double the number of keywords, the expected
桶的数目 在我们加倍关键词数目的同时 那么预期的
look up time doesn't change. For the other possibilities, well if
查询时间并不会改变 对于其他的可能性
we double the number of keywords and keep the same number of
如果我们加倍了关键词数目 保持桶数目不变
buckets, that's going to get slower because the number of keywords
这会使得查询变慢 因为每个桶的关键词数目
per bucket will approximately double. So it's going to take about twice
变成了大约是原来的两倍 所以每次查找需要
as long for each look up. If we keep the same
两倍的时间 如果我们保持同样的
number of keywords, but double the number of buckets, well then it's
关键词数量 但是加倍桶的数目 那么
going to actually get faster. We'll have the same number of keywords, double
查询时间会更快 我们有相同的关键词数目 加倍了
the number of buckets. So, this value will be approximately half of
桶数目 所以 这个值大约是之前的一半
what it was before. The expected lookup time will be about
预期的查找时间将大约是
half of what is before we doubled the number of buckets. If
我们将桶数目加倍之前的一半
we halve the number of keywords keeping the same number of buckets,
我们减半关键词数目 保持桶数目不变
well that has essentially the same affect. The average number of keywords
这本质上与之前有着相同的影响 每个桶的平均关键词数目
per bucket will be half of what it
将会是之前的一半
was before, so the expected lookup time will be
预期的查询时间
about half of what it was. And finally
也会减半 最后呢
if we have both, well that's going to keep
如果我们都减半的话
the ratio the same so the expected look
这将会保持比值相同
up time will be about the same. So that's
预期查询时间也会相同 所以这就是
why these two are the correct answers, that those
为什么这两个是正确的答案 它们的
are expected to leave the lookup time essentially unchanged.
查询时间与预期查询时间基本上保持不变